so let's talk about the fabrication
yield which is what is the percentage of
chips at the end that we get to sell so
the yield is the number of working chips
we get at the end divided by the total
number of chips that we actually had on
a wafer we will see that the size of the
chip affects the yield so it is not only
that we get fewer chips when they're big
but also that a smaller percentage of
them work so let's say this is our wafer
and the wafer typically has a few spots
on it that we call defects it is either
because the silicon was impure to begin
with or because there was something
wrong with the process at that place so
in the end once we get a manufactured
wafer pretty much through a given
manufacturing process there will be some
number of expected defects per wafer so
let's say that this wafer has two
defects let's say that we divide this
wafer into a lot of small chips so note
that some of the chips are not really
complete because of the wafer roundness
we can only use the complete ones so
this is a good chip so we got 62 working
chips and two dead chips so our yield is
62 out of 64 which is about 97% now
let's start with the same wafer and the
same defects but now let's have much
larger chips now we have six working and
two bad chips so our yield is only 75%
so not only did we get fewer chips out
of our expensive wafer we also get a
fewer percentage of them working